Hazel Diamond Macy Diaries D.516
University of Rochester
Hazel Diamond Macy diaries
1855-2012
University of Rochester Rush Rhees Library 500 Joseph C. Wilson Blvd Rochester, New York 14627 rchives@library.rochester.edu http://www.library.rochester.edu
Macy, Hazel Marjorie Diamond, 1885-1957
D.516
7.75 Linear Feet (18 containers)
Biographical / Historical
Hazel Marjorie Diamond Macy was born on March 2, 1885, in Rochester, NY, to Juliet Noyles Diamond and Eliott Barrows Diamond. Macy was involved in her mother's dance studio, Diamond School of Dancing, as a prominent dancer in shows and theater productions. She studied art at the Mechanic's Institute (now Rochester Institute of Technology, RIT) beginning in 1905, graduating in 1907. Afterward, she attended the Boston Museum School, to continue her training. Although she was a ballroom dance instructor during her teenage years and early 20s, after art school, Macy eventually became an art teacher, at the Deaf and Mute Institute, now the National Technical Institute for the Deaf (NTID), where she worked for 8 years.
Macy was very social; she was involved in dances, parties, and events at public halls. She was also a devout Christian Scientist, believing Christian Science as the root of all the good things in her life. She married Paul Macy (1890-1962) in 1916 and had two children. She moved from Rochester to Westchester County in 1928, and died in Scarsdale, NY, on September 6, 1957, from heart disease, at the age of 72. She was cremated, and her ashes are interred at the Mount Hope Cemetery in Rochester, NY.
Scope and Contents
The Hazel Diamond Macy diaries, 1855-2012, the bulk of which document the writer's daily life from 1898-1942. The collection is arranged into three series: Diaries, Manuscripts and Printed Matter, and Photographs.
There are the 166 personal diaries written by Macy. Also included in the collection is a diary written by her husband, Paul Macy, from 1916, which provides an account of their wedding, among other topics. Some diaries are missing covers and pages and must be handled with care. They span topics of social events, family life, education, working, and marriage and children. Macy diaries show that she was very active and social. During her lifetime she witnessed a lot of developments in technology, such as the phonograph, automobile, radio, telephone, moving pictures, airplanes, and cameras, which she notes in her diaries.
In addition to the diaries, there is a scrapbook from the Diamond School of Dancing, including programs, newspaper reviews, and a booklet on ballroom dancing. Please note: some pages of the scrapbook are glued together, and cannot be separated. Also included, is Macy's granddaughter, Melissa Carr Kupfer's, graduate thesis (2004), which provides insight into the time-period when her grandmother lived, and intimate details about her grandmother's life. The correspondence in the collection consists of 3 thank you notes, and a photocopy of a letter from her uncle Jesse Noyes, written during the Civil War.
The papers also consist of 11 stereographs of the Rochester area, including High Falls, and of Niagara Falls, and 38 Pocket Kodak photographs of Macy and family, the Rochester area, and her family farm. There are photocopies of photographs of Macy at age 1, 20 and 30, and of her husband, Paul.
Arrangement
Series I: Diaries: Arranged in chronological order by diary number and date.
Series II: Manuscripts and printed matter: Arranged by subject in alphabetical order.
Subseries I: Dance
Subseries II: Family
Subseries III: Local history
Series III: Photographs: Arranged by format and subject in alphabetical order.
Subseries I: Family
Subseries II: Local history
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Melissa Carr Kupfer, 2017.
Dancers; Teachers; Diaries; Photographs; Macy, Hazel Marjorie Diamond, 1885-1957
- Series I: Diaries, 1898-1942
  - Very First, 1898 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Numbers 1-4, 1899 (Box 1, Folder 2-5)
  - Numbers 5-8, 10-11, 1900 (Box 1, Folder 6-11)
  - Number 12, 1900-1901 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Numbers 13-19, 1901 (Box 2, Folder 1-7)
  - Numbers 20-23, 1902 (Box 2, Folder 8-11)
  - Numbers 24-26, 1902 (Box 3, Folder 1-3)
  - Numbers 27-31, 1903 (Box 3, Folder 4-8)
  - Numbers 32-34, 1904 (Box 3, Folder 9-11)
  - Number 35, 1904-1905 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Numbers 36-37, 1905 (Box 4, Folder 2-3)
  - Number 38, 1905-1906 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Numbers 39-40, 1906 (Box 4, Folder 5-6)
  - Number 41, 1906-1907 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Numbers 42-43, 1907 (Box 4, Folder 8-9)
  - Number 44, 1907-1908 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Numbers 45-46, 1908 (Box 4, Folder 11-12)
  - Number 47, 1908 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Number 48, 1908-1909 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Numbers 49-51, 1909 (Box 5, Folder 3-5)
  - Numbers 52-54, 1910 (Box 5, Folder 6-8)
  - Number 55, 1910-1911 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Numbers 56-57, 1911 (Box 5, Folder 10-11)
  - Number 58, 1911-1912 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Number 59, 1912 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Number 60, 1912-1913 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Numbers 61-62, 1913 (Box 6, Folder 3-4)
  - Number 63, 1913-1914 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Number 64-65, 1914 (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
  - Number 66, 1914-1915 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Number 67, 1915 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Number 68, 1915-1916 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Numbers 69-70, 1916 (Box 7, Folder 6-7)
  - Number 71, 1916-1917 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Numbers 72-74, 1917 (Box 7, Folder 9-11)
  - Number 75, 1917-1918 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Number 76, 1918 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Number 77, 1918-1919 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Number 78, 1919 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Number 79, 1919-1920 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Number 80, 1920 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Number 81, 1920-1921 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Numbers 82-84, 1921 (Box 8, Folder 7-9)
  - Number 85, 1921-1922 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Number 86, 1922 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Number 87, 1922 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Number 88, 1922-1923 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Numbers 89-93, 1923 (Box 9, Folder 3-7)
  - Number 94, 1923-1924 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Numbers 95-98, 1924 (Box 9, Folder 9-12)
  - Number 99, 1924-1925 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Numbers 100-102, 1925 (Box 10, Folder 2-4)
  - Number 103, 1925-1926 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Numbers 104-107, 1926 (Box 10, Folder 6-9)
  - Number 108, 1926-1927 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Numbers 109-110, 1927 (Box 10, Folder 11-12)
  - Number 111, 1927-1928 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Number 112, 1928 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Number 113, 1928-1929 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Number 114, 1929-1930 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Numbers 115-117, 1930 (Box 11, Folder 5-7)
  - Number 118, 1930-1931 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Number 119, 1931 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Number 120, 1931-1932 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Numbers 121-124, 1932 (Box 12, Folder 2-5)
  - Number 125, 1932-1933 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Numbers 126-130, 1933 (Box 13, Folder 1-5)
  - Number 131, 1933-1934 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Numbers 132-136, 1934 (Box 13, Folder 7-11)
  - Number 137, 1934-1935 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Numbers 138-140, 1935 (Box 14, Folder 1-3)
  - Number 141, 1935-1936 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Numbers 142-143, 1936 (Box 14, Folder 5-6)
  - Number 144, 1936-1937 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Numbers 145-146, 1937 (Box 14, Folder 8-9)
  - Number 147, 1937-1938 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Numbers 148-149, 1938 (Box 14, Folder 11-12)
  - Number 150, 1938 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Number 151, 1938-1939 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Numbers 152-154, 1939 (Box 15, Folder 3-5)
  - Number 155, 1939-1940 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Numbers 156-157, 1940 (Box 15, Folder 7-8)
  - Number 158, 1940-1941 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Numbers 159-161, 1941 (Box 15, Folder 10-12)
  - Number 162, 1941 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Number 163, 1941-1942 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Numbers 164-166, 1942 (Box 16, Folder 3-5)
  - Excerpts from diary of Hazel Diamond Macy, 1898-1924 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Diary by Paul Macy, 1916 (Box 17, Folder 1)
- Series II: Manuscripts and printed matter, 1855-1916
  - Subseries I: Dance, 1872-1903
    - Ballroom dancing booklet, 1872 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Contracts between Mrs. Juliet M. Diamond and the Humane Society of Rochester, NY, 1898 (Box 17, Folder 3-4)
    - Diamond School of Dancing programs, 1896-1899 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Lyceum Theatre programs, 1899 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Newspaper clippings from dancing productions, 1899 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Scrapbook of newspaper clippings, 1898-1903 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Subseries II: Family, 1855-2004
    - Correspondence, 1898-1899 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Lists of debt owed, 1855 (Box 17, Folder 10)
      Scope and Contents
      Believed to be family related.
    - Melissa Carr Kupfer Master's thesis (Granddaughter), 2004 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Photocopy of Civil War letter from Jesse Noyes (uncle), 1864 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Spelling test of Hazel Diamond, 1899 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Subseries III: Local history, 1875, 1907
    - Brick Church Life programs, 1907 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous ephemera, 1875 (Box 17, Folder 15)
- Series III: Photographs
  - Subseries I: Family, 1886-1930
    - Photocopies of Photographs of Hazel Diamond Macy and Paul Macy, 1886-circa 1930 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Pocket Kodak photos, circa 1896-1902 (Box 18, Folder 1-39)
      Original box cover states, "The Locusts" Diamond Family Farm, Morton, NY.
  - Subseries II: Local history, circa 1880s-1890s
    - Stereograph cards, circa late 1880s-1890s (Box 17, Folder 17)